Okay, we've talked about how to size our experiment, what comes next?
我们已经学习了如何确定实验规模 接下来要学习什么？
>> Well we have to translate our ideal size into a set of practical decisions.
我们得将理想规模转变为一系列切实可行的决定
First of all, what's the duration of the experiment that I want to run?
首先 我要持续开展实验多长时间？
Secondly, when do I want to run the experiment?
第二 我要在什么时候开展实验？
Is, you know, back to school a good time to run it?
返校时间是不是一个好时机？
What about holidays?
节假日呢？
Is it going to overlap something that's important and
它会不会与其他一些重要活动有冲突？
then third you have to think about what fraction of your traffic you're going to
第三 你得考虑要在实验期间
send through the experiment.
发送多少比例的流量
Those are all interrelated as they get you to the ideal size but
这些因素彼此相关 可帮助你计算理想规模
you need to think about them a little bit separately.
但你得单独考虑它们中的每一项
>> The fist two make sense.
我觉得前两点很有道理
Could you go over the last one a little bit more?
你可以详细讲解一下第三点吗？
>> Sure.
好的
So what's that your unit of diversion is a cookie.
假设分组单元为 cookie
And so what we're really asking is on any given day
我们关注的是
what proportion or what percentage of the cookies are you sending to your
在指定一天中有多少比例的 cookie
experiment and your control?
将发送至实验组和对照组？
Now, let's say we're and we need 1 million cookies in our experiment and
假设我们需要为实验组和对照组采集
our control combined.
共计 100 万个 cookie
Now, if you only get a 100,000 cookies visiting your site on any given day.
如果在指定某天中只有 100,000 个 cookie 访问你的网站
That means that if you want to run 50% of
假设你将 50% 的流量
your traffic through the experiment and
发送给实验组
50% through the control, you need to run your experiment control for ten days.
将剩余 50% 的流量发送给对照组 那么你的实验需要持续十天
Now, another choice is to run your experiment at 25% each, say,
另一种方案是向实验中的每个组发送 25% 的流量
it's because you want to run another test,
因为你还想执行其他测试
then you'd have to run your experiment for 20 days as opposed to 10.
这时 你的实验需要持续开展 20 天 而不是之前的 10 天
And that's how, the duration of your experiment, is related to the proportion
实验持续时间与你在实验期间所发送的流量比例
of traffic that you're sending through your experiment.
的关系就是这样
Okay, why wouldn't you always run on all of your traffic so
你为什么不总是针对所有流量开展实验？
you can get results quicker?
这样不是能更快获得结果吗？
>> Well, there's a couple of different reasons.
原因有好几个
The first, which we've touched on before, is safety.
首先是安全性 我们之前曾提及这一点
So basically, you may have a new UI feature, and you're not sure either how
在推出新的用户界面功能时 你不确定它是否能在所有浏览器中正常运行
well it functions in all browsers, or I mean, hopefully you know.
也许你能确定这一点
But you may want to test it.
但你想测试一下
Or how your users are going to react.
你也不确定用户将有什么反应
So they might get frustrated with it.
他们可能会觉得新功能不好用
It might not work that well.
新功能可能没有你设想般完美
So you might want to actually keep the site mostly the same, and
所以你可能想让网站基本维持现状
only expose a few people to it until you feel more comfortable with it.
仅向部分用户开展实验 直到你获得满意结果
The other reason would be something like press.
第二个原因是压力
Let's say it's a new feature.
假设你推出了一个新功能
You're not really sure you're going to keep it.
但你不确定将来是不是会保留它
Do you really want a lot of people seeing this and potentially blogging
当你还不确定是否要将这个功能在网站上线的时候
about if you're not sure it's even going to be the way you go with the site?
你会希望很多人看到它并在博客上大肆宣扬吗？
>> So, another reason is that right now we're randomizing across the unit of
另一个理由是 现在我们随机分配分组单元
diversion, but the question is what
但问题是
other things are actually impacting the variability of your results?
还有什么因素会实际影响结果的差异性？
Carrie mentioned something at the beginning of this video which is about
Carrie 在这个视频开始的时候提到了一些因素
you know, what if it ran on a holiday, right?
例如 如何遇到节假日怎么办？
Well, you know, if you're running a 50-50 experiment,
在采用一半一半的流量分配开展实验时
then you can gather all data on a single day, would you actually want to
你将采集一天中的所有数据
make a decision based on a single day if it was a holiday?
但如果这一天是节假日 你会希望用这天的数据来做决策吗？
Well, a more common scenario is that you have to have very different behavior
另一个更常见的情景是
on weekdays and weekends.
工作日与周末的行为通常存在很大差异
And so you might actually prefer to run at a smaller percentage across multiple
所以以你可能会倾向于针对较小比例的流量开展一个持续多天的实验
days to get a sense for how the differences are by week day and weekend,
从而了解工作日与周末、节假日
across holidays, by different times of day, all of those different types of
以及一天中的不同时段之间的差异
things that you are actually accounting for those other sources of variability.
以及所有其他可能导致差异性的因素
>> And the other option is, you may be running multiple tasks at your company
另一个方案是 你可以在公司开展多个实验任务
or you may be running multiple tasks of the same feature with you know,
或者针对相同功能开展多个实验任务
different levels of a parameter or different types of the same feature?
并为不同任务设置不同水平的参数 或者针对相同功能的不同类型开展实验
And if you really want those things to be directly comparable, the easiest
如果你想直接对比这些方面
thing to do is to run them at the same time on smaller percentages of traffic.
就简单的方式就是针对较小比例的流量同时开展这些实验
And then you know that if one of the tests was affected by a holiday or
当其中一个测试受节假日或流量的某个奇怪变化影响时
a strange shift in your traffic, they all were, and you should be able to
所有测试都会有相同反应
compare the relative ordering of the tests against each other.
你就能对比这些有着相对顺序的测试了
>> Got it.
明白了